// src/data/questions.js

export const questions = [
    { question: "	Express 19/8 as a mixed number?",
       options: ["A. 3 4/8", "B. 2 3/8", "C. 18", "D. 24"],
        correctAnswer: "B. 2 3/8" },
    { question: "2.	Express 2/5 as a percentage ?",
      options: ["	A. 50%","B. 40%","C. 48%","D. 45%",], 
      correctAnswer: "B. 40%" },
    { question: "3. 2P-P-P  is equal to _____?",
       options: ["A. 2p", "B. 0", "C. -p", "D. 4p"],
        correctAnswer: "B. 0" },
    { question: "  4.	If a divides b which is a/b, then the number a on top is called ______?",
          options: ["A. numerator", "B. denominator", "C. fraction ", "D. decimal"],
           correctAnswer: "A. numerator" },
    { question: " 5.	Express Â¾ as percentage?",
            options: ["A. 70%", "B. 75%", "C. 35%", "D. 40%"],
             correctAnswer: "B. 75%" },
    { question: " 6.	What is 25% of 200?",
              options: ["A. 25", "B. 50", "C. 75", "D. 100"],
               correctAnswer: "B. 50" },
    { question: " 7.	If a shirt originally costs $40 and is on sale for $30, what is the percentage discount?",
                options: ["A. 10%", "B. 15%", "C. 25%", "D. 30%"],
                 correctAnswer: "C. 25%" },
     { question: " 8.	A student scored 80 out of 100 in a test. What is his percentage score?",
                  options: ["A. 70%", "B. 80%", "C. 85%", "D. 90%"],
                   correctAnswer: "B. 80%" },
     { question: "9. A number that is at the bottom In a improper fraction is called _____?",
                    options: ["A. numerator", "B. denominator", "C. solicitator", "D. none "],
                     correctAnswer: "B. denominator" },
    { question: "10.	5p-3p+ 2p",
                      options: ["A. 4p", "B. 0p", "C. 9p", "D. 10p"],
                       correctAnswer: "A. 4p" },
    { question: "11.	Convert 0.75 to a fraction in simplest form:",
                        options: ["A. 3/4", "B. 2/3","	C. 1/2","D. 5/6"],
                         correctAnswer: "A. 3/4" },
   { question: "12.	What is the sum of 0.5 and 0.25?",
                          options: ["A. 4p", "B. 0p", "C. 9p", "D. 10p"],
                           correctAnswer: "A. 4p" },
   { question: "13.		If you multiply 0.6 by 100, what do you get?",
                            options: ["A. 66", "B. 60", "C. 600", "D. 0"],
                             correctAnswer: "B. 60" },
   { question: "14.	 	What is the difference between 1.1 and 0.0.?",
                              options: ["A. 0.0", "B. 1.1", "C. 2.2", "D. None of These"],
                               correctAnswer: "B. 1.1" },
    { question: "15.	Which decimal is equivalent to the fraction 15/10.",
                                options: ["A. 1.5", "B. 0.2", "C. 0.5", "D. 0.15"],
                                 correctAnswer: "A. 1.5" },
    { question: "16.	Solve for x in the equation: 2x+3=11.",
                                  options: ["A. x=8", "B. x=7", "C. x=4", "D. x=5"],
                                   correctAnswer: "C. x=4" },
    { question: "17.	X + x + x + x =?",
                                    options: ["A. 4x", "B. x", "C. 99", "D. 3x"],
                                     correctAnswer: "C. 99" },
    { question: "18.	What is the solution to the equation 3x=x+12?",
                                      options: ["A. x=6", "B. x=3", "C. x=125", "D. x=12"],
                                       correctAnswer: "B. x=3" },
    { question: "19.	If 5a+a=6 what is the value of a?",
                                        options: ["A. a=1", "B. a=2", "C. a=None of These"],
                                         correctAnswer: "A. a=1" },
    { question: "20.	What is the value of x in the equation 4x -5=5-x?",
                                          options: ["A. x=5", "B. x=2", "C. x=3", "D. x=None of These"],
                                           correctAnswer: "B. x=2" },
   { question: "21. 	Which of the following is a characteristic of living things?",
                      options: ["A. They do not grow", "B. They Reproduce", "C. They cannot respond to stimuli", "D. They do not need energy"],
                                            correctAnswer: "B. They Reproduce" },
   { question: "22. 	Which of the following is an example of a non-living thing?",
                                            options: ["A. Plant", "B. Animal", "C. Rock", "D. Bacteria"],
                                             correctAnswer: "C. Rock" },
  { question: "23.	Which among the  following is the state of matter",
                     options: ["A. living, nonliving and semi living", "B. grass, desk and oxygen", "C. solid, liquid and gas", "D. hot, cold and watery"],
                                              correctAnswer: "C. solid, liquid and gas" },
  { question: "24.	Which of the following is NOT a characteristic of living things?",
                                  options: ["A. Growth", "B. Reproduction", "C. Respiration", "D. Inertia"],
                                               correctAnswer: "D. Inertia" },
  { question: "25.	Which of the following is among the causes of drug abuse",
                                               options: ["A. Reduction of stress and frustration", "B. Opium", "C. Valium", "D. None"],
                                                correctAnswer: "B. Opium" },
  { question: "26.	One of the following is not a soil waste?",
                                                options: ["A. Plastic", "B. Vegetable matter", "C. Shoe", "D. None"],
                                                 correctAnswer: "C. Shoe" },
 { question: "27.	One of the following is a plants that we use as medicine?",
                                                 options: ["A. Shoe", "B. Maringa", "C. Egg", "D. Grass"],
                                                  correctAnswer: "B. Maringa" },
 { question: "28.	What is the primary purpose of drug rehabilitation?",
                                 options: ["A. To provide legal advice.", "B. To help individuals overcome addiction.", "C. To promote drug use.", "D. To increase drug availability."],
                                                   correctAnswer: "B. To help individual overcome addiction" },
{ question: "29.	Which term describes a condition where a person cannot control their drug use?",
                                options: ["A. Tolerance", "B. Addiction", "C. Dependence", "D. Withdrawal"],
                                                    correctAnswer: "B. Addiction" },
 { question: "30.	_______ is the discharge of waste substances?",
                                options: ["A. Drug", "B. Chemical", "C. Petrol", "D. Pollution"],
                                                     correctAnswer: "B. Chemical" },
 { question: "31.	What is pollution?",
                               options: ["A. The introduction of harmful substances into the environment.", "B. The process of cleaning up waste.", "C. The growth of plants in an area.", "D. The movement of animals from one place to another."],
                                                      correctAnswer: "A. The introduction of harmful substances into the environment." },
 { question: "32.		Which type of pollution is primarily caused by vehicle emissions?",
                              options: ["A. Water pollution", "B. Air pollution", "C. Soil pollution", "D. Noise pollution"],
                                                       correctAnswer: "B. Air pollution" },
 { question: "33.		Which gas is a major contributor to climate change?",
                              options: ["A. Oxygen", "B. Carbon dioxide", "C. Nitrogen", "D. Hydrogen"],
                                                        correctAnswer: "B. Carbon dioxide" },
 { question: "34.	What can individuals do to reduce pollution?",
                                                        options: ["A. Use plastic bags", "B. Recycle materials", "C. Drive more often", "D. Waste water"],
                                                         correctAnswer: "B. Recycle materials" },
{ question: "35.	Yam, garri, millet are example of ________?",
                              options: ["A. minerals", "B. Carbohydrates", "C. Fiber and water", "D. Sugars only"],
                                                          correctAnswer: "B. Carbohydrates" },
  { question: "36.	________ is a chemical or substance which affect the action of the body?",
                                                          options: ["A. drug", "B. Chemical", "C. Petrol", "D. diesel"],
                                                           correctAnswer: "A. Drug" },
 { question: "37.	What is the primary function of carbohydrates in the diet?",
                                                           options: ["A. Build muscle", "B. Provide energy", "C. Regulate body temperature", "D. Strengthen bones"],
                                                            correctAnswer: "B. Provide energy" },
  { question: "38.	Which food group should be consumed in moderation to maintain a healthy diet?",
                                                            options: ["A. Fruits and vegetables", "B. Grains", "C. Fat and Oil", "D. Proteins"],
                                                             correctAnswer: "C. Fat and Oil" },
 { question: "39.	What was the name of the first computer designed by Charles Babbage?",
                           options: ["A. Analytical Engine", "B. Difference engine", "C. Colossus", "D. ENIAC"],
                          correctAnswer: "B. Difference engine" },                                 
 { question: "40.	Second generation computer started from 1956 ______	",
                          options: ["A. 2024", "B. 1964", "C. 1963", "D. None"],
                         correctAnswer: "C. 1963" },
  { question: "41.	The importance of technology is to _______",
                         options: ["A. produce food", "B. mprove lives", "C. Destroy lives", "D. None"],
                        correctAnswer: "B. Improve lives" },
 { question: "42.	______ is an instrument that is used for arithmetic calculations",
                        options: ["A. Abacus", "B. mechanical", "C. Barometer", "D. thermometer"],
                       correctAnswer: "A. Abacus" },
{ question: "43.	Technology can be define as the technical means that people use to improve their ____",
                       options: ["A. Data", "B. Lives", "C. Environment", "D. Laptop"],
                      correctAnswer: "B. Lives" },
 { question: "44.	What is data processing?",
                      options: ["A. The collection of data only.", "B. The manipulation and organization of data to produce meaningful information.", "C. The storage of data in a database.", "D. The deletion of unnecessary data"],
                     correctAnswer: "B. The manipulation and organization of data to produce meaningful information." },
 { question: "45.	Which of the following is NOT a type of data processing?",
                     options: ["A. Batch processing", "B. Real-time processing", "C. Manual processing", "D. Digital processing"],
                    correctAnswer: "D. Digital processing" },
  { question: "46.	What is Batch processing_________ ?",
                    options: ["A. Processing data in real-time.", "B. Processing data in groups at scheduled times.", "C. Processing data one at a time.", "D. Processing data without any input."],
                   correctAnswer: "B. Processing data in groups at scheduled times." },
  { question: "47.	Which device is primarily used for data entry?",
                   options: ["A. Monitor", "B. Printer", "C. Keyboard", "D. Harddrives"],
                  correctAnswer: "C. Keyboard" },
  { question: "48.	What does data mining refer to?",
                  options: ["A. Collecting raw data.", "B. Analyzing large datasets to discover patterns and relationships.", "C. Deleting of Unnecessary files", "D. Backing up information."],
                 correctAnswer: "B. Analyzing large datasets to discover patterns and relationships." },
 { question: "49.	Which generation of computers used vacuum tubes?",
                 options: ["A. 1st generation", "B. 2nd Generation", "C. 3rd generation", "D. 4th generation"],
                correctAnswer: "A. 1st generation" },
  { question: "50.	What technology characterized the 2nd generation of computers?",
                options: ["A. Vacuum tubes", "B. Transistors", "C. Integrated circuits", "D. Microprocessors"],
               correctAnswer: "B. Transistors" },
 { question: "51.	Which generation is known for using Very Large Scale Integration circuits?",
               options: ["A. 1st generation", "B. 2nd generation", "C. 3rd generation", "D. 4th generation"],
              correctAnswer: "D. 4th generation" },
  { question: "52.	What does ULSI stand for in computing?",
              options: ["A. Ultra Large Scale Integration", "B. Unified Large Scale Integration", "C. Ultra Low Scale Integration", "D. Under Large Scale Integration"],
             correctAnswer: "A. Ultra Large Scale Integration" },                 
  { question: "53.	Which generation introduced the use of artificial intelligence",
             options: ["A. 1st generation", "B. 2nd generation", "C. 3rd generation", "D. 5th generation"],
            correctAnswer: "D. 5th generation" },
 { question: "54.	What is Moore's Law?",
            options: ["A. The number of transistors on a microchip doubles approximately every two years.", "B. Computers will become obsolete in ten years.", "C. Software will always be free.", "D. Technology will never improve after a certain point."],
           correctAnswer: "A. The number of transistors on a microchip doubles approximately every two years." },
  { question: "55.	Which technology allows multiple computers to communicate over a network?",
           options: ["A. Cloud computing", "B. Virtual reality", "C. Artificial Intelligence", "D. Data Mining"],
          correctAnswer: "A. Cloud computing" },
  { question: "56.	What is cloud computing primarily used for?",
               options: ["A. Storing and accessing data over the internet instead of on a local computer.", "B. Running applications on a personal computer only.", "C. Improving hardware performance.", "D. Creating physical copies of documents."],
              correctAnswer: "D. 4th generation" },
  { question: "57.	Through technology we invented the following_________?",
              options: ["A. man, women, boy, water and sky", "B. engine, machine, radio, television and computer", "C. None", "D. All"],
             correctAnswer: "B. engine, machine, radio, television and computer" },
 { question: "58.	What does AI stand for in technology?",
             options: ["A. Automated Intelligence", "B. Artificial Intelligence", "C. Advanced Information", "D. Automated Information"],
            correctAnswer: "B. Artificial Intelligence" },
{ question: "59.	What is agriculture primarily concerned with?",
            options: ["A. Manufacturing goods", "B. Cultivating crops and raising animals", "C. Mining resources", "D. Urban development"],
           correctAnswer: "B. Cultivating crops and raising animals" },
{ question: "60.	Why is agriculture important for society?",
           options: ["A. It provides entertainment.", "B. It supports food security and economic development.", "C. It reduces population growth.", "D. It promotes urbanization."],
          correctAnswer: "B. It supports food security and economic development." },
 { question: "61.	Which of the following is not among the importance of agriculture?",
          options: ["A. food production", "B. Biennials", "C. Help industry", "D. Annual"],
         correctAnswer: "B. Biennials" },
 { question: "62.	What role does agriculture play in the economy?",
           options: ["A. It is the least important sector.", "B. It provides jobs and income for millions.", "C. It only benefits rural areas.", "D. It has no impact on trade."],
             correctAnswer: "B. It provides jobs and income for millions." },
 { question: "63.	Which of the following is NOT among the forms of agriculture?",
               options: ["A. horticulture", "B. soil science", "C. Snail rearing", ],
              correctAnswer: "C. Snail rearing" },
 { question: "64.	Crop plants is the study of the structure of crops and how to take care of them as they grow.",
              options: ["A. True", "B. False", "C. None", "D. All"],
             correctAnswer: "A. True" },
{ question: "65.	The technical name for farm animal is called  ______",
             options: ["A. crop", "B. Mammals", "C. Livestock", "D. None"],
            correctAnswer: "C. Livestock" },
 { question: "66.	What type of crop is typically grown for industrial purposes?",
            options: ["A. Food crops", "B. Cash crops", "C. Fiber crops", "D. Oranmental crops"],
           correctAnswer: "C. Fiber crops" },
 { question: "67.	Which crop is known for its high protein content and is often used in livestock feed?",
           options: ["A. Corn", "B. Wheat", "C. Soybean", "D. Barley"],
           correctAnswer: "C. Soybean" },
 { question: "68.	What is horticulture focused on?",
          options: ["A. Growing grains", "B. Cultivating fruits, vegetables, and ornamental plants", "C. Raising livestock", "D. Aquaculture"],
         correctAnswer: "B. Cultivating fruits, vegetables, and ornamental plants" },
 { question: "69.	Which animal is commonly raised for milk production?",
         options: ["A. Sheep", "B. Goat", "C. Cow", "D. Pig"],
        correctAnswer: "C. Cow" },
  { question: "70.	What type of farming involves raising chickens for eggs and meat?",
        options: ["A. Aquaculture", "B. Poultry farming", "C. Apiculture", "D. Horticulture"],
       correctAnswer: "B. Poultry farming" },
 { question: "71.	Which farm animal is primarily raised for its wool?",
       options: ["A. Cow", "B. Goat", "C. Sheep", "D. Pig"],
      correctAnswer: "C. Sheep" },
  { question: "72. What is the primary purpose of raising pigs in agriculture?",
      options: ["A. Milk production", "B. Meat production", "C. Wool production", "D. Egg production"],
     correctAnswer: "B. Meat production" },
  { question: "73.	------- provide all our food as well as raw material?",
     options: ["A. Basic science", "B. Agriculture", "C. Maths", "D. Computer"],
    correctAnswer: "B. Agriculture" },                        
  { question: "74.	What is subsistence agriculture?",
    options: ["A. Farming primarily for profit with large-scale production.", "B. Farming to provide food mainly for the farmer's family.", "C. Farming that uses advanced technology only.", "D. Farming that focuses on cash crops exclusively."],
   correctAnswer: "B. Farming to provide food mainly for the farmer's family." },
  { question: "75. Which form of agriculture involves growing multiple crops simultaneously on the same land?",
   options: ["A. Monoculture", "B. Mixed cropping", "C. Shifting cultivation", "D. Intensive farming"],
  correctAnswer: "B. Mixed Cropping" },
  { question: "76. What does commercial agriculture focus on?",
       options: ["A. Producing food only for local consumption.", "B. Maximizing profits through large-scale production.", "C. Using traditional farming methods exclusively.", "D. Minimizing environmental impact only."],
       correctAnswer: "B. Maximizing profits through large-scale production." },
     { question: "77.	Which type of farming involves moving livestock to find fresh pastures?",
            options: ["A. Intensive farming", "B. Nomadic pastoralism", "C. Mixed farming", "D. Subsistence farming"],
            correctAnswer: "B. Nomadic pastoralism" },
     { question: "78.	What is aquaculture?",
       options: ["A. The cultivation of plants in gardens.", "B. The rearing of fish and other aquatic organisms.", "C. The practice of keeping bees for honey", "D. The farming of lands animal only"],
           correctAnswer: "B. The rearing of fish and other aquatic organisms." },
      { question: "79.	What is technology?",
            options: ["A. The study of ancient artifacts", "B. The application of scientific knowledge for practical purposes", "C. A form of entertainment", "D. The process of farming"],
             correctAnswer: "B. The application of scientific knowledge for practical purposes" },
     { question: "80. The three types of matter are arranged as __________",
            options: ["A. solid ,liquid and gas", "B. gas ,liquid and solid", "C. solid gas liquid", "D. Liquid   gas    solid"],
           correctAnswer: "A. solid ,liquid and gas" },
  { question: "81.	_______ can be defined as open knowledge, ideas, skills, and procedures for making or doing things in specifiable and repeatable ways.",
           options: ["A. Solving problems", "B. Technology", "C. Air pollution", "D. None"],
          correctAnswer: "B. Technology" },
  { question: "82.	_______ Makes things happen, makes things possible and efficient for the comfort and ease of human life?",
          options: ["A. Agriculture", "B. Technology", "C. Nutrition", "D. Communication"],
         correctAnswer: "B. Technology" },
 { question: "83. What is the primary function of an operating system?",
         options: ["A. To manage hardware and software resources", "B. To create documents", "C. To browse the internet", "D. To play games"],
        correctAnswer: "A. To manage hardware and software resources" },
  { question: "84. What is the purpose of safety guidelines in technology use?",
        options: ["A. To increase productivity", "B. To protect users from harm and ensure proper use of equipment", "C. To reduce cost", "D. To enhance performance only"],
       correctAnswer: "B. To protect users from harm and ensure proper use of equipment" },
  { question: "85. Which of the following is a common safety guideline when using electronic devices?",
       options: ["A. Using devices near water without caution", "B. Keeping devices away from overheating sources", "C. Ignoring Manufacturing Instruction", "D. Using damaged cables"],
      correctAnswer: "B. Keeping devices away from overheating sources" },
  { question: "86. What should you do if an electronic device shows signs of smoke or burning?",
      options: ["A. Continue using it", "B. Unplug it immediately and seek help", "C. Pour water on it", "D. Ignore it"],
     correctAnswer: "B. Unplug it immediately and seek help" },
 { question: "87. Which personal protective equipment is essential when working with chemicals in a lab?",
               options: ["A. Gloves only", "B. Safety goggles only", "C. Lab coat only", "D. Gloves, goggle, and lab coat "],
            correctAnswer: "D. Gloves, goggle, and Lab coat" },
  { question: "88. What is the first step to take in case of an electrical shock?",
               options: ["A. Touch the person to check their response", "B. Call for help immediately", "C. Move the person to safety without precautions", "D. Use water to cool them down"],
            correctAnswer: "B. CAll ofr help immediately" },
 { question: "89. Which device is used to convert electrical energy into light energy?",
          options: ["A. Battery", "B. Resistor", "C. Light bulb", "D. Capacitor"],
          correctAnswer: "C. Light bulb" }, 
  { question: "90. What is the function of a capacitor in electronic circuits?",
            options: ["A. To store electrical energy temporarily", "B. To convert AC to DC", "C. To amplify signals", "D. To provide resistance"],
             correctAnswer: "A. To store electrical energy temporarily" },
 { question: "91. Which component is essential for controlling the flow of electricity in a circuit?",
             options: ["A. Diode", "B. Switch", "C. Inductor", "D. Transformer"],
                correctAnswer: "B. Switch" },
 { question: "92. What does a diode do in an electronic circuit?",
         options: ["A. It stores energy", "B. It allows current to flow in one direction only", "C. It amplify signals", "D. It converts energy types"],
        correctAnswer: "B. It allows current to flow in one direction only" },   
 { question: "93. Which device converts sound waves into electrical signals?",
                options: ["A. Speaker", "B.  Microphone", "C. Amplifier", "D. Oscillator"],
                correctAnswer: "B.  Microphone" },
 { question: "94. What defines matter?",
              options: ["A. Anything that has mass and takes up space.", "B. Only solid object", "C. Only living organisms.", "D. Only liquid"],
             correctAnswer: "A. Anything that has mass and takes up space." },             
  { question: "95. Which property describes how well a substance can conduct electricity?",
              options: ["A. Density", "B. Conductivity", "C. Solubility.", "D. Magnetism"],
               correctAnswer: "B. Conductivity." },
 { question: "96. What is density?",
              options: ["A. The mass per unit volume of a substance.", "B. The total mass of an object.", "C. The amount of space an object occupies.", "D. The temperature at which a substance melt"],
              correctAnswer: "A. The mass per unit volume of a substance." },
   { question: "97. Which state of matter has a definite shape and volume?",
           options: ["A.Solid.", "B. Liquid", "C. Gas", "D. Plasma"],
             correctAnswer: "A. Solid." },
  { question: "98. What is a chemical property of matter?",
             options: ["A. Color change during heating.", "B. Melting point", "C. Density measurement.", "D. Volume measurement"],
               correctAnswer: "A. Color change during heating." },
{ question: "99. how many colors  made  the rainbow?",
                options: ["A. 7.", "B. 8", "C. 5.", "D. 2"],
                  correctAnswer: "A. 7" },
{ question: "100. how many stomach chamber does a cattle have?",
                        options: ["A. 4", "B. 2", "C. 3", "D. 8"],
                          correctAnswer: "A. 4" },
];
      